<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/">
<channel rdf:about="https://slashdot.org/">
<title>Slashdot</title>
<link>https://slashdot.org/</link>
<description>News for nerds, stuff that matters</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 1997-2016, SlashdotMedia. All Rights Reserved.</dc:rights>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T19:53:17+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>Dice</dc:publisher>
<dc:creator>help@slashdot.org</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Technology</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1970-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>hourly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
<rdf:Seq>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/1922237/why-major-newspapers-didnt-publish-ufo-retrieval-story?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/184255/apples-future-airpods-could-take-your-temperature-offer-hearing-tests?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0140223/100-bands-including-ratm-boycott-venues-using-facial-recognition-technology?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0055253/microsofts-light-based-transistor-less-computer-solves-complex-optimization-problems-at-the-speed-of-light?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2248234/despite-amazon-ban-flipper-zeros-multi-tool-device-for-hackers-on-track-for-80m-in-sales?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0346241/linux-foundations-yocto-project-expands-lts-to-4-years?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0126245/could-a-solar-superstorm-someday-trigger-an-internet-apocalypse?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0222215/second-largest-us-ev-fast-charging-network-will-also-add-tesla-connectors?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0251224/could-amds-ai-chips-match-the-performance-of-nvidias-chips?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0117210/gizmodo-and-kotaku-staff-furious-after-owner-announces-test-of-ai-content?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0457237/should-uk-stores-use-facial-recognition-tech-to-fight-shoplifting?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2129221/insects-could-help-turn-beer-waste-into-beef?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2056200/ecological-doom-loops-why-ecosystem-collapses-may-occur-sooner-than-expected?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1939222/microsoftactivision-blizzard-antitrust-hearings-reveal-internal-emails-and-badly-redacted-documents?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
<rdf:li rdf:resource="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1721241/spacex-launches-esas-euclid-space-telescope-to-study-dark-energys-effect-on-the-universe?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed"/>
</rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/topics/topicslashdot.gif"/>
<textinput rdf:resource="https://slashdot.org/search.pl"/>
</channel>
<image rdf:about="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/topics/topicslashdot.gif">
<title>Slashdot</title>
<url>https://a.fsdn.com/sd/topics/topicslashdot.gif</url>
<link>https://slashdot.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/1922237/why-major-newspapers-didnt-publish-ufo-retrieval-story?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Why Major Newspapers Didn't Publish 'UFO Retrieval' Story</title>
<link>https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/1922237/why-major-newspapers-didnt-publish-ufo-retrieval-story?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>Monday U.S. Senator Marco Rubio said government workers with high security clearances had made UFO-related claims, leading to a bill's provision to halt any reverse-engineering of alien crafts. News stories at the time noted "allegations of secret UFO retrieval and reverse-engineering programs" by former intelligence official turned whistleblower, David Grusch, a story which Vanity Fair traced to a "little-known" site called The Debrief. But that article's authors have some serious journalistic experience. Ralph Blumenthal spent more than 45 years on staff at The New York Times. Leslie Kean is an investigative science journalist known for her writing on UFOs. In 2017 they teamed up with a New York Times Pentagon correspondent for an "explosive 2017 UFO report," writes the Atlantic, "in which the journalists revealed a defunct secret Pentagon program &mdash; initially funded at the request of former Senate majority leader Harry Reid &mdash; to investigate 'unidentified flying objects.'" I've learned that Kean and Blumenthal did, in fact, bring the story to the Times, but the paper of record turned it down... The pair also pitched their story to Politico and The Washington Post. The Post had been trying to further report the story that the reporters had brought to the paper, but didn't think it was ready for publication; among its reservations, according to a source familiar, was that it was unclear what members of Congress made of Grusch's testimony... Politico &mdash; which, a source familiar noted, had the story for mere days, while the Post had the story for weeks &mdash; also wasn't able to turn around the story at the speed that Kean and Blumenthal wanted, Blumenthal said... The writers' apparent time constraints have only raised more questions. "To be clear &mdash; the Washington Post did not pass on our story," Kean wrote on Facebook Monday. "Ralph and I took it to the Debrief because we were under growing pressure to publish it very quickly." Blumenthal told me that circumstances &mdash; including that Grusch's identity as the whistleblower had leaked out on the internet &mdash; pushed them to "publish sooner than we'd hoped." "If there had been no leaks, it might've been different," Blumenthal said. But "people on the internet were spreading stories Dave was getting harassing phone calls and we felt the only way to protect him was to get the story out...." Now out in the world, the reporting process is raising even more eyebrows. During interviews on NewsNation with both Grusch and Kean, it became clear that neither had seen photos of the alleged craft. NewsNation's Brian Entin asked Kean about the lack of receipts: "He has the credentials, but there's no documents that he's handed over, there's no pictures, and as a journalist, you want to see documents; you want to see pictures." But Kean said the lack of documents or photographs did not raise red flags for her because "all of that information is classified." She believes it, she said, "because of all the sources I have who have told me the same thing... I don't think there's some conspiracy among all these people who don't know each other to make something like this up." In response to the report, DoD spokesperson Sue Gough told NewsNation in a statement, "To date, AARO (All-domain Anomaly Resolution Office) has not discovered any verifiable information to substantiate claims that any programs regarding the possession or reverse-engineering of any extraterrestrial materials have existed in the past or exist currently.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Why+Major+Newspapers+Didn't+Publish+'UFO+Retrieval'+Story%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fentertainment.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F1922237%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fentertainment.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F1922237%2Fwhy-major-newspapers-didnt-publish-ufo-retrieval-story%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/1922237/why-major-newspapers-didnt-publish-ufo-retrieval-story?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22956076&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T19:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>scifi</dc:subject>
<slash:department>take-me-to-your-leaders</slash:department>
<slash:section>entertainment</slash:section>
<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>6,6,5,4,0,0,0</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/184255/apples-future-airpods-could-take-your-temperature-offer-hearing-tests?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Apple's Future AirPods Could Take Your Temperature, Offer Hearing Tests</title>
<link>https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/184255/apples-future-airpods-could-take-your-temperature-offer-hearing-tests?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>The Verge reports: Some AirPods will be gaining a new hearing health feature, supported by iOS 17, that can check yourself for potential hearing issues and may be able to determine your body temperature via your ear canal, according to Bloomberg's Mark Gurman in today's Power On newsletter. He also says all of Apple's new headphones will include USB-C, and that the company is planning new AirPods Pro and AirPods Max models &mdash; but he doesn't think new hardware is coming soon. AirPods already support audiograms &mdash; audio profiles that tell the AirPods where your hearing may be weakest so that they can tune themselves to your hearing abilities. Right now, you can generate an audiogram using the app Mimi, which Apple would be Sherlocking &mdash; an infamous Apple tendency to fold third-party features and apps into its operating system &mdash; with a built-in hearing test feature... Gurman says Apple is also exploring positioning the AirPods as hearing aids, now that the FDA has approved over-the-counter sales of hearing aids without a prescription... Gurman believes the new health features are "several months or even years away," and that although USB-C AirPods may be coming soon, AirPods Pro themselves are so far on a three-year refresh cycle.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Apple's+Future+AirPods+Could+Take+Your+Temperature%2C+Offer+Hearing+Tests%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fapple.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F184255%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fapple.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F184255%2Fapples-future-airpods-could-take-your-temperature-offer-hearing-tests%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/184255/apples-future-airpods-could-take-your-temperature-offer-hearing-tests?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22956016&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T18:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>apple</dc:subject>
<slash:department>boogie-fevers</slash:department>
<slash:section>apple</slash:section>
<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>6,6,4,4,0,0,0</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0140223/100-bands-including-ratm-boycott-venues-using-facial-recognition-technology?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>100 Bands Including RATM Boycott Venues Using Facial Recognition Technology</title>
<link>https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0140223/100-bands-including-ratm-boycott-venues-using-facial-recognition-technology?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>Rolling Stone reports: Over 100 artists including Rage Against the Machine co-founders Tom Morello and Zack de la Rocha, along with Boots Riley and Speedy Ortiz, have announced that they are boycotting any concert venue that uses facial recognition technology, citing concerns that the tech infringes on privacy and increases discrimination. The boycott, organized by the digital rights advocacy group Fight for the Future, calls for the ban of face-scanning technology at all live events. Several smaller independent concert venues across the country, including the House of Yes in Brooklyn, the Lyric Hyperion in Los Angeles, and Black Cat in D.C., also pledged to not use facial recognition tech for their shows. Other artists who said they would boycott include Anti-Flag, Wheatus, Downtown Boys, and over 80 additional artists. The full list of signatories is available here. "Surveillance tech companies are pitching biometric data tools as 'innovative' and helpful for increasing efficiency and security. Not only is this false, it's morally corrupt," Leila Nashashibi, campaigner at Fight for the Future, said in a statement. "For starters, this technology is so inaccurate that it actually creates more harm and problems than it solves, through misidentification and other technical faultiness. Even scarier, though, is a world in which all facial recognition technology works 100% perfectly &mdash; in other words, a world in which privacy is nonexistent, where we're identified, watched, and surveilled everywhere we go...." New York venue Citi Field as well as Cleveland's FirstEnergy Stadium, Miami's Hard Rock Stadium, and the Pechanga Arena in San Diego are among several venues across the country that have used face-scanning. Thanks to long-time Slashdot reader SonicSpike for sharing the story.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=100+Bands+Including+RATM+Boycott+Venues+Using+Facial+Recognition+Technology%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fentertainment.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0140223%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fentertainment.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0140223%2F100-bands-including-ratm-boycott-venues-using-facial-recognition-technology%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://entertainment.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0140223/100-bands-including-ratm-boycott-venues-using-facial-recognition-technology?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955388&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T17:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>ai</dc:subject>
<slash:department>facing-the-music</slash:department>
<slash:section>entertainment</slash:section>
<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>24,24,19,17,1,0,0</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0055253/microsofts-light-based-transistor-less-computer-solves-complex-optimization-problems-at-the-speed-of-light?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Microsoft's Light-Based, Transistor-less Computer Solves Complex Optimization Problems at the Speed of Light</title>
<link>https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0055253/microsofts-light-based-transistor-less-computer-solves-complex-optimization-problems-at-the-speed-of-light?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>"Picture a world where computing is not limited by the binary confines of zeros and ones, but instead, is free to explore the vast possibilities of continuous value data." That's Microsoft's research blog, describing its newly-developed Analog Iterative Machine, an analog optical computer designed for solving difficult optimization problems. "For a multidisciplinary group of researchers at the Microsoft Research Lab in Cambridge, U.K., the mission was to build a new kind of computer that would transcend the limitations of the binary systems," says a Microsoft blog post. Neowin describes it as a computer "that uses photons and electrons, rather than transistors, to process data." Light "passes through several layers, making impressions on each part of what's known as a 'modular array'," writes PC Gamer. "It's this process of projecting light through the array that replaces the function of a standard transistor." Microsoft says it can "solve practical problems at the speed of light." And "it's already shown potential for surpassing state-of-the art digital (silicon-based) technology," adds TechSpot, "or even the most powerful quantum computers being designed right now." The AIM machine is built using commodity opto-electronic technologies that are low-cost and scalable, Microsoft says, and is based on an "asynchronous data flow architecture" which doesn't require data exchange between storage units and "compute locations." AIM isn't designed for general purpose computing tasks, though. The analog optical computer is useful to solve difficult "optimization problems" like the well-known travelling salesman riddle, Microsoft says, which are at the heart of many, math-intensive industries including finance, logistics, transportation, energy, healthcare, and manufacturing. When it comes to crunching all the possible combinations of an exponentially growing problem, traditional, digital computers struggle to provide a solution in a "timely, energy-efficient and cost-effective manner." AIM was conceived to address two simultaneous trends, Microsoft explains, which are sidestepping the unraveling of Moore's Law and overcoming the limitations of specialized machines designed for solving optimization problems... AIM works at the speed of light, and it seemingly provides a 100x increase in performance compared to the most advanced digital approaches available today. For now, AIM is still a research project with limited access for potential customers. The machine, however, is already being tested by UK financial company Barclays, which is using it to track transactions of money into stock purchases. Microsoft says it's now releasing its "AIM simulator as a service, allowing selected users to get first-hand experience. The initial users are the team's collaborators at Princeton University and at Cambridge University."<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Microsoft's+Light-Based%2C+Transistor-less+Computer+Solves+Complex+Optimization+Problems+at+the+Speed+of+Light%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fhardware.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0055253%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fhardware.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0055253%2Fmicrosofts-light-based-transistor-less-computer-solves-complex-optimization-problems-at-the-speed-of-light%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0055253/microsofts-light-based-transistor-less-computer-solves-complex-optimization-problems-at-the-speed-of-light?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955366&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T16:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>microsoft</dc:subject>
<slash:department>light-reading</slash:department>
<slash:section>hardware</slash:section>
<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>25,25,22,19,6,3,2</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2248234/despite-amazon-ban-flipper-zeros-multi-tool-device-for-hackers-on-track-for-80m-in-sales?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Despite Amazon Ban, Flipper Zero's 'Multi-Tool Device for Hackers' On Track for $80M in Sales</title>
<link>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2248234/despite-amazon-ban-flipper-zeros-multi-tool-device-for-hackers-on-track-for-80m-in-sales?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>The company behind Flipper Zero expects $80 million in sales this year, which ZDNet estimates at around 500,000 unit sales. In its Kickstarter days the company sold almost $5 million as preorders, remembers TechCrunch, and the company claims it sold $25 million worth of the devices last year: So what are they selling? Flipper Zero is a "portable gamified multi-tool" aimed at everyone with an interest in cybersecurity, whether as a penetration tester, curious nerd or student &mdash; or with more nefarious purposes. The tool includes a bunch of ways to manipulate the world around you, including wireless devices (think garage openers), RFID card systems, remote keyless systems, key fobs, entry to barriers, etc. Basically, you can program it to emulate a bunch of different lock systems. The system really works, too &mdash; I'm not much of a hacker, but I've been able to open garages, activate elevators and open other locking systems that should be way beyond my hacking skill level. On the one hand, it's an interesting toy to experiment with, which highlights how insecure much of the world around us actually is. On the other hand, I'm curious if it's a great idea to have 300,000+ hacking devices out in the wild that make it easy to capture car key signals and gate openers and then use them to open said apertures. The company points out that their firmware is open source, and can be inspected by anyone. ZDNet calls it "incredibly user-friendly" and "a fantastic educational tool and a stepping stone to get people &mdash; young and old &mdash; into cybersecurity," with "a very active community of users that are constantly finding new things to do with it". (Even third-party operating systems are available). "Instead of looking like some scary hacking tool, all black and bristling with antennas, it looks like a kid's toy, all plastic and brightly colored," writes ZDNet. "It reminds me of Tamagotchis..." Thanks to Slashdot reader ZipNada for suggesting the article.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Despite+Amazon+Ban%2C+Flipper+Zero's+'Multi-Tool+Device+for+Hackers'+On+Track+for+%2480M+in+Sales%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fit.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F2248234%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fit.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F2248234%2Fdespite-amazon-ban-flipper-zeros-multi-tool-device-for-hackers-on-track-for-80m-in-sales%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2248234/despite-amazon-ban-flipper-zeros-multi-tool-device-for-hackers-on-track-for-80m-in-sales?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955298&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T15:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>security</dc:subject>
<slash:department>Kickstarted</slash:department>
<slash:section>it</slash:section>
<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>25,25,23,22,7,3,2</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0346241/linux-foundations-yocto-project-expands-lts-to-4-years?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Linux Foundation's Yocto Project Expands LTS to 4 Years</title>
<link>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0346241/linux-foundations-yocto-project-expands-lts-to-4-years?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>Wikipedia defines the Yocto Project as "a Linux Foundation collaborative open source project whose goal is to produce tools and processes that enable the creation of Linux distributions for embedded and IoT software that are independent of the underlying architecture of the embedded hardware." This week the Linux Foundation shared an update on the 12-year-old Yocto Project: In an effort to support the community, The Yocto Project announced the first Long Term Support (LTS) release in October 2020. Today, we are delighted to announce that we are expanding the LTS release and extending the lifecycle from 2 to 4 years as standard. The continued growth of the Yocto Project coincides with the welcomed addition of Exein as a Platinum Member, joining AMD/Xilinx, Arm, AWS, BMW Group, Cisco, Comcast, Intel, Meta and WindRiver. As a Member, Exein brings its embedded security expertise across billions of devices to the core of the Yocto Project... "The Yocto Project has been at the forefront of OS technologies for over a decade," said Andrew Wafaa, Yocto Project Chairperson. "The adaptability and variety of the tooling provided are clearly making a difference to the community. We are delighted to welcome Exein as a member as their knowledge and experience in providing secure Yocto Project based builds to customers will enable us to adapt to the modern landscape being set by the US Digital Strategy and the EU Cyber Resilience Act." "We're extremely excited to become a Platinum Partner of the Yocto Project," said Gianni Cuozzo, founder and CEO of Exein. "The Yocto Project is the most important project in the embedded Linux space, powering billions of devices every year. We take great pride in contributing our extensive knowledge and expertise in embedded security to foster a future that is both enhanced and secure for Yocto-powered devices. We are dedicated to supporting the growth of the Yocto Project as a whole, aiming to improve its support for modern languages like Rust, and assist developers and OEMs in aligning with the goals outlined in the EU Cyber Resilience Act." <p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Linux+Foundation's+Yocto+Project+Expands+LTS+to+4+Years%3A+https%3A%2F%2Flinux.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F0346241%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Flinux.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F0346241%2Flinux-foundations-yocto-project-expands-lts-to-4-years%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0346241/linux-foundations-yocto-project-expands-lts-to-4-years?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22954520&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T14:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>opensource</dc:subject>
<slash:department>longer-term-support</slash:department>
<slash:section>linux</slash:section>
<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>3,3,3,2,0,0,0</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0126245/could-a-solar-superstorm-someday-trigger-an-internet-apocalypse?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Could a Solar Superstorm Someday Trigger an 'Internet Apocalypse'?</title>
<link>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0126245/could-a-solar-superstorm-someday-trigger-an-internet-apocalypse?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>"Black Swan events are hard-to-predict rare events that can significantly alter the course of our lives," begins a 2021 paper by a computer science professor at the University of California. Now the Washington Post revisits that exploration of the possibility that "magnetic fields unleashed by a solar superstorm rip through Earth's magnetosphere, sending currents surging through human infrastructure." A widespread internet outage could, indeed, be brought on by a strong solar storm hitting Earth &mdash; a rare but very real event that has not yet happened in the digital age, experts say. When a solar storm known as the Carrington Event struck in 1859, telegraph lines sparked, operators were electrocuted and the northern lights descended to latitudes as low as Jamaica. A 1989 solar storm took out the Quebec power grid for hours. And in 2012, a storm just missed Earth. As the sun, which has roughly 11-year cycles, enters a particularly active period known as the "solar maximum" in 2025, some are worried our interconnected world is not prepared. Sangeetha Abdu Jyothi, a computer science professor at University of California at Irvine whose paper "Solar Superstorms: Planning for an Internet Apocalypse" has played a role in popularizing the term, started thinking about internet resilience when the coronavirus began to spread, and she realized how unprepared we were for a pandemic. Research on widespread internet failure was scant. "We've never experienced one of the extreme case events, and we don't know how our infrastructure would respond to it," Jyothi said. "Our failure testing doesn't even include such scenarios." She notes that a severe solar storm is likely to affect large-scale infrastructure such as submarine communication cables, which could interrupt long-distance connectivity. If you have not lost power, you might have access to, say, a government website hosted locally, but reaching bigger websites, which could have data stored all over the place, might not be possible. The northern latitudes are also especially vulnerable to solar storms, and that's where a lot of internet infrastructure is concentrated. "This is not taken into account in our infrastructure deployment today at all," she said. Such outages could last for months, depending on the scale and how long it takes to repair the damage. The economic impact of just one day of lost connectivity in the United States alone is estimated to be more than $11 billion, according to the internet watcher NetBlocks. Still, Jyothi says she has felt bad for using the term "internet apocalypse" in her paper. There's not much ordinary people can do to prepare for such a phenomenon; it falls on governments and companies. And the paper "just got too much attention," she said. "Astrophysicists estimate the likelihood of a solar storm of sufficient strength to cause catastrophic disruption occurring within the next decade to be 1.6 to 12%," the paper concludes. (It also notes that the U.S. has a higher risk for a disconnection than Asia.) "Paying attention to this threat and planning defenses against it, like our preliminary effort in this paper, is critical for the long-term resilience of the Internet."<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Could+a+Solar+Superstorm+Someday+Trigger+an+'Internet+Apocalypse'%3F%3A+https%3A%2F%2Ftech.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F0126245%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftech.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F0126245%2Fcould-a-solar-superstorm-someday-trigger-an-internet-apocalypse%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0126245/could-a-solar-superstorm-someday-trigger-an-internet-apocalypse?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22954434&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T11:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>internet</dc:subject>
<slash:department>here-comes-the-sun</slash:department>
<slash:section>technology</slash:section>
<slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>70,70,64,57,16,10,7</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0222215/second-largest-us-ev-fast-charging-network-will-also-add-tesla-connectors?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Second-Largest US EV Fast-Charging Network Will Also Add Tesla Connectors</title>
<link>https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0222215/second-largest-us-ev-fast-charging-network-will-also-add-tesla-connectors?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>Earlier this week the Society of Automotive Engineers, a U.S.-based standards organization, announced plans to support Tesla's EV "North American Charging Standard" (or NCAS). The Verge reported Tuesday that "With SAE supporting NACS, larger EV charging company holdouts like the Volkswagen-owned Electrify America may have an easier time making the jump." And two days later, they did. The Associated Press reports: The second-largest electric vehicle fast-charging network in the U.S. says it will add Tesla's connector to its charging stations, another step toward adopting Tesla's plug as the industry standard. Electrify America, with 800 direct-current fast-charging stations and more than 3,600 plugs nationwide, said Thursday it will work to add Tesla's connector to existing and future chargers by 2025. The Volkswagen subsidiary, formed as part of the settlement to the company's diesel emissions-cheating scandal, is second only to Tesla in number of fast-charging plugs in the U.S. "We look forward to continuing to support industrywide standards that increase vehicle interoperability and streamline public charging," Electrify America CEO Robert Barrosa said in a statement. The company also will keep the Combined Charging System, or CCS, connector at its stations. At present most electric vehicle models in the U.S. use the CCS connector. But Ford, General Motors, Rivian and Volvo have said they would join Tesla's large Supercharger network and adopt its North American Charging Standard connector in new versions of their electric vehicles. Others such as Stellantis and Hyundai are considering joining Tesla's network. Also, ChargePoint, which has the most charging stations of any U.S. network, said it will start offering Tesla connectors for use by charging site hosts later this year... Others, such as Blink Charging also have announced plans to add the Tesla connector. <p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Second-Largest+US+EV+Fast-Charging+Network+Will+Also+Add+Tesla+Connectors%3A+https%3A%2F%2Ftech.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0222215%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftech.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0222215%2Fsecond-largest-us-ev-fast-charging-network-will-also-add-tesla-connectors%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0222215/second-largest-us-ev-fast-charging-network-will-also-add-tesla-connectors?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955404&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T07:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>transportation</dc:subject>
<slash:department>charging-ahead</slash:department>
<slash:section>technology</slash:section>
<slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>50,49,48,45,5,4,3</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0251224/could-amds-ai-chips-match-the-performance-of-nvidias-chips?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Could AMD's AI Chips Match the Performance of Nvidia's Chips?</title>
<link>https://slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0251224/could-amds-ai-chips-match-the-performance-of-nvidias-chips?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>An anonymous reader shared this report from Reuters: Artificial intelligence chips from Advanced Micro Devices are about 80% as fast as those from Nvidia Corp, with a future path to matching their performance, according a Friday report by an AI software firm. Nvidia dominates the market for the powerful chips that are used to create ChatGPT and other AI services that have swept through the technology industry in recent months. The popularity of those services has pushed Nvidia's value past $1 trillion and led to a shortage of its chips that the Nvidia says it is working to resolve. But in the meantime, tech companies are looking for alternatives, with hopes that AMD will be a strong challenger. That prompted MosaicML, an AI startup acquired for $1.3 billion earlier this week, to conduct a test comparing between AI chips from AMD and Nvidia. MosaicML evaluated the AMD MI250 and the Nvidia A100, both of which are one generation behind each company's flagship chips but are still in high demand. MosaicML found AMD's chip could get 80% of the performance of Nvidia's chip, thanks largely to a new version of AMD software released late last year and a new version of open-source software backed by Meta Platforms called PyTorch that was released in March.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Could+AMD's+AI+Chips+Match+the+Performance+of+Nvidia's+Chips%3F%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fslashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0251224%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fslashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0251224%2Fcould-amds-ai-chips-match-the-performance-of-nvidias-chips%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0251224/could-amds-ai-chips-match-the-performance-of-nvidias-chips?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955416&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T04:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>amd</dc:subject>
<slash:department>chipping-away</slash:department>
<slash:section>slashdot</slash:section>
<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>28,28,26,25,7,3,2</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0117210/gizmodo-and-kotaku-staff-furious-after-owner-announces-test-of-ai-content?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Gizmodo and Kotaku Staff Furious After Owner Announces Test of AI Content</title>
<link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0117210/gizmodo-and-kotaku-staff-furious-after-owner-announces-test-of-ai-content?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>Futurism reports: G/O Media, a major online media company that runs publications including Gizmodo, Kotaku, Quartz, Jezebel, [the Onion], and Deadspin, has announced that it will begin a "modest test" of AI content on its sites... In an email to staff, G/O Media editorial director Merrill Brown argued that the news shouldn't come as a surprise since "everyone in the media business" has been considering AI. The trial will include "producing just a handful of stories for most of our sites that are basically built around lists and data," Brown wrote. "These features aren't replacing work currently being done by writers and editors, and we hope that over time if we get these forms of content right and produced at scale, AI will, via search and promotion, help us grow our audience..." Unions representing G/O Media and The Onion staff issued a statement, writing that "we are appalled by this news. The hard work of journalists cannot be replaced by unreliable AI programs notorious for creating falsehoods and plagiarizing the work of real writers." Gizmodo and Kotaku staff, in particular, were outraged at the news. "AI content will not replace my work &mdash; but it will devalue it, place undue burden on editors, destroy the credibility of my outlet, and further frustrate our audience," Gizmodo journalist Lin Codega tweeted in response to the news. "AI in any form, only undermines our mission, demoralizes our reporters, and degrades our audience's trust." <p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Gizmodo+and+Kotaku+Staff+Furious+After+Owner+Announces+Test+of+AI+Content%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fnews.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0117210%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fnews.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F02%2F0117210%2Fgizmodo-and-kotaku-staff-furious-after-owner-announces-test-of-ai-content%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/02/0117210/gizmodo-and-kotaku-staff-furious-after-owner-announces-test-of-ai-content?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955380&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-02T01:45:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>ai</dc:subject>
<slash:department>rise-of-the-machines</slash:department>
<slash:section>news</slash:section>
<slash:comments>116</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>116,106,79,60,24,15,9</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0457237/should-uk-stores-use-facial-recognition-tech-to-fight-shoplifting?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Should UK Stores Use Facial Recognition Tech to Fight Shoplifting?</title>
<link>https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0457237/should-uk-stores-use-facial-recognition-tech-to-fight-shoplifting?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>The New York Times tells the story of Simon Mackenzie, a security officer at a U.K. discount store uploading security camera footage of shoplifters into a facial recognition program called Facewatch. "The next time those people enter any shop within a few miles that uses Facewatch, store staff will receive an alert." Facewatch &mdash; now in nearly 400 stores across Britain &mdash; licenses facial recognition software made by Real Networks and Amazon. Though it only sends alert about repeat offenders, "Once added, a person remains there for a year before being deleted." For as little as 250 pounds a month, or roughly $320, Facewatch offers access to a customized watchlist that stores near one another share. When Facewatch spots a flagged face, an alert is sent to a smartphone at the shop, where employees decide whether to keep a close eye on the person or ask the person to leave. Mr. Mackenzie adds one or two new faces every week, he said, mainly people who steal diapers, groceries, pet supplies and other low-cost goods. He said their economic hardship made him sympathetic, but that the number of thefts had gotten so out of hand that facial recognition was needed. Usually at least once a day, Facewatch alerts him that somebody on the watchlist has entered the store... Among democratic nations, Britain is at the forefront of using live facial recognition, with courts and regulators signing off on its use. The police in London and Cardiff are experimenting with the technology to identify wanted criminals as they walk down the street. In May, it was used to scan the crowds at the coronation of King Charles III. But the use by retailers has drawn criticism as a disproportionate solution for minor crimes. Individuals have little way of knowing they are on the watchlist or how to appeal. In a legal complaint last year, Big Brother Watch, a civil society group, called it "Orwellian in the extreme...." Madeleine Stone, the legal and policy officer for Big Brother Watch, said Facewatch was "normalizing airport-style security checks for everyday activities like buying a pint of milk." There is a human in the loop, the article points out. "Every time Facewatch's system identifies a shoplifter, a notification goes to a person who passed a test to be a 'super recognizer' &mdash; someone with a special talent for remembering faces. Within seconds, the super recognizer must confirm the match against the Facewatch database before an alert is sent." The company's founder tells the Times that in general, "mistakes are rare but do happen... If this occurs, we acknowledge our mistake, apologize, delete any relevant data to prevent reoccurrence and offer proportionate compensation." And the article adds this official response from the U.K. government: Fraser Sampson, Britain's biometrics and surveillance camera commissioner, who advises the government on policy, said there was "a nervousness and a hesitancy" around facial recognition technology because of privacy concerns and poorly performing algorithms in the past. "But I think in terms of speed, scale, accuracy and cost, facial recognition technology can in some areas, you know, literally be a game changer," he said. "That means its arrival and deployment is probably inevitable. It's just a case of when."<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Should+UK+Stores+Use+Facial+Recognition+Tech+to+Fight+Shoplifting%3F%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fyro.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F0457237%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fyro.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F0457237%2Fshould-uk-stores-use-facial-recognition-tech-to-fight-shoplifting%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/0457237/should-uk-stores-use-facial-recognition-tech-to-fight-shoplifting?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22954584&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-01T22:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>ai</dc:subject>
<slash:department>robo-cops</slash:department>
<slash:section>yro</slash:section>
<slash:comments>90</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>90,86,71,60,11,5,4</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2129221/insects-could-help-turn-beer-waste-into-beef?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Insects Could Help Turn Beer Waste Into Beef</title>
<link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2129221/insects-could-help-turn-beer-waste-into-beef?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>"People do not like eating insects. Livestock are less picky," writes the Economist. Of course, the insects need to eat, too. To date, they have mostly been reared on leftover chicken feed. But the supply of that is limited, and if insect-reared meat is to take off, new sources will be needed. In a paper in Applied Entomology, Niels Eriksen, a biochemist at Aalborg University, suggests feeding them on the waste products of the beer industry. The world knocks back around 185bn litres of beer every year. Each litre produces between three and ten litres of wastewater full of discarded barley and yeast . The mix is rich in protein but deficient in carbohydrates, especially compared with chicken feed. The Economist reports that the researchers found brewery waste was "happily consumed" by insects they tested, which "grew equally well on either food source." This suggests the possibility that other plentiful and protein-rich food wastes could also become "reasonable targets for nutrient recycling by insects," including waste from other fermentation industries (like bioethanol), slaughterhouses, and sugar-beet waste. Thanks to Slashdot reader echo123 for sharing the article.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Insects+Could+Help+Turn+Beer+Waste+Into+Beef%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fnews.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F2129221%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fnews.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F2129221%2Finsects-could-help-turn-beer-waste-into-beef%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2129221/insects-could-help-turn-beer-waste-into-beef?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955248&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-01T21:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>beer</dc:subject>
<slash:department>getting-a-buzz</slash:department>
<slash:section>news</slash:section>
<slash:comments>52</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>52,49,42,31,7,2,2</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2056200/ecological-doom-loops-why-ecosystem-collapses-may-occur-sooner-than-expected?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Ecological Doom Loops: Why Ecosystem Collapses May Occur Sooner Than Expected</title>
<link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2056200/ecological-doom-loops-why-ecosystem-collapses-may-occur-sooner-than-expected?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>An anonymous Slashdot reader writes: An article in Nature Sustainability suggests that models may have underestimated the impact of warming on ecosystems. Two main reasons for this are the difficulty in accounting for variability and combining climate change with other pressure factors: for instance, pollution, excessive exploitation of species, deforestation due to increased demographics growth and meat consumption, ecosystem fragmentation, also harm wildlife. After using software to simulate over 70,000 ecosystem scenarios, the two professors and a postdoctoral researcher issued this warning in The Conversation: Around the world, rainforests are becoming savanna or farmland, savanna is drying out and turning into desert, and icy tundra is thawing. Indeed, scientific studies have now recorded "regime shifts" like these in more than 20 different types of ecosystem where tipping points have been passed. Around the world, more than 20% of ecosystems are in danger of shifting or collapsing into something different. These collapses might happen sooner than you'd think. Humans are already putting ecosystems under pressure in many different ways &mdash; what we refer to as stresses. And when you combine these stresses with an increase in climate-driven extreme weather, the date these tipping points are crossed could be brought forward by as much as 80%. This means an ecosystem collapse that we might previously have expected to avoid until late this century could happen as soon as in the next few decades. That's the gloomy conclusion of our latest research, published in Nature Sustainability. Human population growth, increased economic demands, and greenhouse gas concentrations put pressures on ecosystems and landscapes to supply food and maintain key services such as clean water. The number of extreme climate events is also increasing and will only get worse. What really worries us is that climate extremes could hit already stressed ecosystems, which in turn transfer new or heightened stresses to some other ecosystem, and so on. This means one collapsing ecosystem could have a knock-on effect on neighbouring ecosystems through successive feedback loops: an "ecological doom-loop" scenario, with catastrophic consequences... There is no way to restore collapsed ecosystems within any reasonable timeframe. There are no ecological bailouts. In the financial vernacular, we will just have to take the hit. <p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Ecological+Doom+Loops%3A++Why+Ecosystem+Collapses+May+Occur+Sooner+Than+Expected%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fnews.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F2056200%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fnews.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F2056200%2Fecological-doom-loops-why-ecosystem-collapses-may-occur-sooner-than-expected%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/2056200/ecological-doom-loops-why-ecosystem-collapses-may-occur-sooner-than-expected?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955230&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-01T20:59:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>earth</dc:subject>
<slash:department>games-of-doom</slash:department>
<slash:section>news</slash:section>
<slash:comments>137</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>137,117,94,82,13,3,2</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1939222/microsoftactivision-blizzard-antitrust-hearings-reveal-internal-emails-and-badly-redacted-documents?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>Microsoft/Activision Blizzard Antitrust Hearings Reveal Internal Emails and Badly-Redacted Documents</title>
<link>https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1939222/microsoftactivision-blizzard-antitrust-hearings-reveal-internal-emails-and-badly-redacted-documents?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>VentureBeat is enjoying "secrets that spilled out" in the Microsoft/Activision Blizzard antitrust hearings. "Whether the Federal Trade Commission wins its antitrust case or not, its attempt to stop Microsoft's $68.7 billion acquisition of Activision Blizzard has revealed a trove of new data for everyone." The FTC has argued in a federal court that the merger would harm competition in the game industry and be bad for consumers, as Microsoft could pull Activision Blizzard's games like Call of Duty away from the Sony PlayStation, despite Microsoft's stated intention of not doing so for at least 10 years. In this case, the FTC might not have had an obvious winning hand, as the industry has an odd situation. Microsoft has the highest value ($104 billion in cash alone, versus $13.4 billion for Sony) at $2.49 trillion as a company compared to $115 billion for Sony, and yet it is in third place behind Sony and Nintendo. Hence, there's some significance to Microsoft's Xbox first-party head, Matt Booty, sending an ill-advised email in 2019 saying Microsoft "has the ability to spend Sony out of business." That was long before the deal was announced 17 months ago, but it could be used as a sign of intent. Microsoft said it never pursued this strategy. While competing fiercely is fine, using monopoly power to drive a rival out of business so you can raise prices later is a no-no... Did the FTC prove its case? I can't say just yet. Microsoft makes a decent point in saying all the regulators of the world except the U.S. and the United Kingdom have approved the deal. But I hope to have more reasons to binge on popcorn. In January Ars Technica noted Microsoft's contract set July 18th as the deadline for closing the deal &mdash; or else paying a $3 billion "breakup fee". The Verge spotted that some of Sony's documents were poorly redacted. While looking at the lines that were crossed out with black pens, they could see that The Last of Us Part 2 cost the company $220 million to make, with 200 people working on it, while Horizon Forbidden West cost $212 million to make, with 300 working on it for over five years. Both games made considerably more money... In the unSharpied documents, Sony also revealed that a million Call of Duty players spent 100% of their time playing Call of Duty in 2021. It also said that Call of Duty generated $800 million for PlayStation in 2021 alone in the U.S. and perhaps $1.5 billion globally. It also looks like Sony's exclusive marketing deal with Activision for Call of Duty will expire in late 2023. Sony went on to say half of PS5 owners also have a Nintendo Switch. Microsoft also failed to redact some of its acquisition targets. Those were later marked up, but not before Axios noted that the list included Thunderful, Supergiant Games, Niantic, Playrix, Zynga, Bungie, Square Enix, Warner Bros., Sega, IO Interactive and Scopely... Among the secrets revealed among the companies Microsoft acquired: Microsoft bought Ninja Theory, maker of Hellblade: Senua's Sacrifice, for $117 million. Thanks to Slashdot reader ole_timer for sharing the news.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=Microsoft%2FActivision+Blizzard+Antitrust+Hearings+Reveal+Internal+Emails+and+Badly-Redacted+Documents%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fgames.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F1939222%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fgames.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F1939222%2Fmicrosoftactivision-blizzard-antitrust-hearings-reveal-internal-emails-and-badly-redacted-documents%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1939222/microsoftactivision-blizzard-antitrust-hearings-reveal-internal-emails-and-badly-redacted-documents?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955200&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-01T19:42:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>microsoft</dc:subject>
<slash:department>game-on</slash:department>
<slash:section>games</slash:section>
<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>22,22,16,15,6,1,1</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1721241/spacex-launches-esas-euclid-space-telescope-to-study-dark-energys-effect-on-the-universe?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">
<title>SpaceX Launches ESA's 'Euclid' Space Telescope to Study Dark Energy's Effect on the Universe</title>
<link>https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1721241/spacex-launches-esas-euclid-space-telescope-to-study-dark-energys-effect-on-the-universe?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed</link>
<description>"The European Space Agency's Euclid space telescope launched at 11:12 a.m. ET Saturday," reports CNN, "aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket from Florida's Cape Canaveral Space Force Station. CNN is calling it "a mission designed to unravel some of the greatest mysteries of the universe." The 1.2-meter-diameter (4-foot-diameter) telescope has set off on a monthlong journey to its orbital destination of the sun-Earth Lagrange point L2, which is nearly 1 million miles (1.6 million kilometers) away from Earth and also home to NASA's James Webb Space Telescope... After arriving at orbit, Euclid will spend two months testing and calibrating its instruments &mdash; a visible light camera and a near-infrared camera/spectrometer &mdash; before surveying one-third of the sky for the next six years. Euclid's primary goal is to observe the "dark side" of the universe, including dark matter and dark energy. While dark matter has never actually been detected, it is believed to make up 85% of the total matter in the universe. Meanwhile, dark energy is a mysterious force thought to play a role in the accelerating expansion of the universe. In the 1920s, astronomers Georges Lema&icirc;tre and Edwin Hubble discovered that the universe has been expanding since its birth 13.8 billion years ago. But research that began in the 1990s has shown that something sparked an acceleration of the universe's expansion about 6 billion years ago, and the cause remains a mystery. Unlocking the true nature of dark energy and dark matter could help astronomers understand what the universe is made of, how its expansion has changed over time, and if there is more to understanding gravity than meets the eye... Euclid is designed to create the largest and most accurate three-dimensional map of the universe, observing billions of galaxies that stretch 10 billion light-years away to reveal how matter may have been stretched and pulled apart by dark energy over time. These observations will effectively allow Euclid to see how the universe has evolved over the past 10 billion years... The telescope's image quality will be four times sharper than those of ground-based sky surveys. Euclid's wide perspective can also record data from a part of the sky 100 times bigger than what Webb's camera can capture. During its observations, the telescope will create a catalog of 1.5 billion galaxies and the stars within them, creating a treasure trove of data for astronomers that includes each galaxy's shape, mass and number of stars created per year. Euclid's ability to see in near-infrared light could also reveal previously unseen objects in our own Milky Way galaxy, such as brown dwarfs and ultra-cool stars. In May 2027, Euclid will be joined in orbit by the Nancy Grace Roman Telescope. The two missions will overlap in their study of cosmic acceleration as they both create three-dimensional maps of the universe...Roman will study one-twentieth of the sky in infrared light, allowing for much more depth and precision. The Roman telescope will peer back to when the universe was just 2 billion years old, picking out fainter galaxies than Euclid can see. CNN points out that "While primarily an ESA mission, the telescope includes contributions from NASA and more than 2,000 scientists across 13 European countries, the United States, Canada and Japan." And they also note this statement from Jason Rhodes, a senior research scientist at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory. "With these upcoming telescopes, we will measure dark energy in different ways and with far more precision than previously achievable, opening up a new era of exploration into this mystery." From NASA's announcement: Scientists are unsure whether the universe's accelerated expansion is caused by an additional energy component, or whether it signals that our understanding of gravity needs to be changed in some way. Astronomers will use Roman and Euclid to test both theories at the same time, and scientists expect both missions to uncover important information about the underlying workings of the universe... Less concentrated mass, like clumps of dark matter, can create more subtle effects. By studying these smaller distortions, Roman and Euclid will each create a 3D dark matter map... Tallying up the universe's dark matter across cosmic time will help scientists better understand the push-and-pull feeding into cosmic acceleration. SpaceX tweeted footage of the telescope's takeoff, and the successful landing of their Falcon 9's first stage on a droneship called A Shortfall of Gravitas.<p><div class="share_submission" style="position:relative;"> <a class="slashpop" href="http://twitter.com/home?status=SpaceX+Launches+ESA's+'Euclid'+Space+Telescope+to+Study+Dark+Energy's+Effect+on+the+Universe%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fscience.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F1721241%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png"></a> <a class="slashpop" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fscience.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F07%2F01%2F1721241%2Fspacex-launches-esas-euclid-space-telescope-to-study-dark-energys-effect-on-the-universe%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png"></a> </div></p><p><a href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/23/07/01/1721241/spacex-launches-esas-euclid-space-telescope-to-study-dark-energys-effect-on-the-universe?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22955102&amp;smallembed=1" style="height: 300px; width: 100%; border: none;"></iframe></description>
<dc:creator>EditorDavid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-07-01T17:34:00+00:00</dc:date>
<dc:subject>space</dc:subject>
<slash:department>what's-the-matter</slash:department>
<slash:section>science</slash:section>
<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
<slash:hit_parade>19,17,15,15,8,3,1</slash:hit_parade>
</item>
<textinput rdf:about="https://slashdot.org/search.pl">
<title>Search Slashdot</title>
<description>Search Slashdot stories</description>
<name>query</name>
<link>https://slashdot.org/search.pl</link>
</textinput>
</rdf:RDF>